[Music]
Hi and welcome to this launch event. My
name is Peter Bøgh.
In this short session, I want to
introduce an enhancement to the page
scripting tool that we launched in the
previous release as a preview.
So, page scripting allows customers and
consultants
to record and replay user actions
directly in the web client. For example,
as part of creating user acceptance
tests.
And then that is a way to then offload
developers
and empower these stakeholders,
customers and consultants, to create
tests in a more agile, quicker, and
cost-effective way.
So, I did a thorough walk through of
this new tool in the previous launch
event.
And so, if this is new to you, I
recommend that you watch that session
either before you continue with this or
after.
Because
in this release in this session, we're
going to talk about an enhancement to
that tool.
And at launch, these scripts that were
recorded in the client had to be
replayed in the client as well.
And that involved tedious manual work.
It also made it more complicated to run
a suite of related tests, you know,
across functionality in the application.
And also, it meant that the scripts that
were captured by customers or
consultants could not be utilized by
developers in their inner and outer loop
to capture regressions early.
And so, one of
the most common feedbacks that we got
from partners
since we launched the preview has been,
could there be a way to run the scripts
in a pipeline instead
for automated testing?
And so, in this release, we are enabling
exactly that. We're introducing a
standalone page script replayer that you
can now use, for instance, in CCD
pipeline to run the scripts.
And that script player is distributed as
a node package manager on NPM package
that you can then install latest version
of this from the NPM feed. I provided a
link here where you can see more on
that.
There is no setup required. You just
have to run an install command. But
there are some requirements. You need to
have a node JS and page playwright and
some additional things, but you can read
more about that on the
package site.
Now, with the BC replayer package, you
can now run a selection of scripts in
your environment.
So, that could be a specific set of
scripts. It could also be just all
scripts in a folder using a wildcard.
And we document the different options
for these parameters on the NPM package.
So, as an example, if you want to run
all scripts in a folder in the recording
folder, and you want to run them on just
the localhost client with Windows
authentication, which is the default,
and output then the results of each
script in the same folder,
then you can use a command just NPM
replay. You provide the folder with all
the scripts. There's a wild wildcard
path there for YAML files because the
scripts are based on YAML files. And we
provide then also the start address for
the client to use. And as I said,
Windows authentication is
a default.
Now, this is available already today.
So, you can go
install this replayer and use it in your
pipelines, especially if you have your
own custom DevOps today. Now, we always
recommend having using a managed DevOps
solution,
for instance, go for GitHub or ALOps or
Alpaca, so you don't have to sort of
spend time on building your custom
setup.
And support for the BC replay page
scripting replayer will come out soon in
those different solutions. We will be
focusing, of course, on the AL go for
GitHub. And so, expect that in the near
future.
So that if you're using that, you can
more or less get this for free.
So, the call to actions,
watch, as I mentioned in the beginning,
the launch event recording from last
time on the page scripting tool to
understand what it can do and the
benefit of that tool.
Also, adopt a managed solution
for DevOps. Again, AL go for GitHub,
ALOps, or Alpaca could be options for
that.
If you are customer or consultant, take
advantage of the tool and create user
acceptance tests to ensure the quality
of custom solutions. And as a partner,
take advantage of having those scripts
and run them in pipelines to catch
regressions earlier on during
development
so that you don't have costly impact in
deployments or upgrades because of those
regressions.
Thank you for watching.